Mss.Ms.Coll.200
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Paul Farmer, Jan.30, 1771; 5 1/2" x 7 3/4"; Hancock, John, 1737-1793
    Boston, L.S. 1p. Order to receive Mary Thompson and child into alms house. Presented by Dr. William E.Lingelbach, June 1952.
  - Letter to Charles Thomson, Jan. 29, 1771; Nicola, Lewis, 1717-1807
    Northampton, Photo.of A.L.S. 21p. (from original in the Edward Hand Papers,I,folio 2, in the Historical Society of Penna.) Concerning the deluge. Presented by W.J. Bell,Jr.; Sept.1964.
  - Letter to Daniel Clymer, Feb. 18, 1771; 11" x 8 1/2"; Bond, Phineas, 1749-1815
    Middle Temple T.C. of L. 2p. His life since coming to Middle Temple about two months ago. Presented by David Amram from original in his possession, May 1955.
  - Letter to David Hume, March 1, 1771; 13x8; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, Typed L. 4p. Copy. Ohio company business. His publications. Politics.
  - Letter to Evert Bancker, Jr., New York, March 27, 1771; 12-1/2x8; Du Simitière, Pierre Eugène, ca. 1736-1784
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. Thanks for pamphlet. Concerning his collection of writings. Concerning the APS Transactions. Film 38
  - Letter to Evert Bancker, Jr., New York, March 31, 1771; 8x6-1/4; Du Simitière, Pierre Eugène, ca. 1736-1784
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the death of his friend, John Smith of Burlington. Film 38
  - Letter to Joshua Sharpe, April 28, 1771; 9" x 7 1/4"; Hughes, Edward, Sir, ca. 1720-1794
    Sheerness, L.S. 1p. and add., end. Mr. Franklin's preparation to return to America; and proposed arrest. FILM54-61 FRAME201
  - Marriage certificate of John Bartram and Elizah Howell, May 9, 1771; 8 1/2" x 11"; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typescript 2p. Presented by Francis D. West,1950; original at Historical society of Pennsylvania
  - Letter to Daniel Clymer, Phila., Aug. 26, 1771; 8" x 6 1/4"; Bond, Phineas, 1749-1815
    Middle Temple, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Purchase of books.
  - Receipt to Anthony Wayne for surveying lands for Franklin, Hughes and Wayne in Nova Scotia, Sept. 12, 1771; 8x7-1/2; Clarkson, Matthew
    Philadelphia, A.D.S. 1p.and end. FILM54-67 FRAME 142
  - Letter to Daniel Clymer, Phila., Oct. 2, 1771; 9 1/2" x 7 1/4"; Bond, Phineas, 1749-1815
    Middle Temple, A.L.S. 1p. and add. and end. Purchase of books.
  - Will, April 26, Oct. 4, 1771, 1775; Brooke, Richard, 1716-1783
    Photo.of D.S. 3p. (from original in Maryland Hall of Records.)
  - Letter to John Lukens, Sept.27, 1772; 7 1/2" x 12 1/2"; Scull, William, fl. 1765
    Reading, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Relative to fees due him for making surveys.
  - Returns made [for surveying?;]., June, 1772; 2-1/2x8-1/4; Scull, William, fl. 1765
  - Will, Jan. 17, 1772; 8" x 13"; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Typescript. 5 leaves Presented by Francis D. West,1950.
  - Letter to David Hall, Philadelphia, April 1, 1772; 9x7-1/4; Strahan, William, 1715-1785
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Forwards books and brass rule. Royal family marriage act. Trial of Clive and need to restrain the East India Company. Politics.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Battista] Beccaria, Oct. 9, 1772; 6 1/2" x 8 1/2"; Saussure, Horace Bénédict de, 1740-1799
    Turin, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French.
  - Receipt to Jonathan Sargeant for salary, June 10, 1773; 3-1/2x7-3/4; Witherspoon, John, 1723-1794
    Princeton, A.D.S. 1p. and end. Presented by Morris Duane; 12/30/69.
  - Will, July 14, 1773; 12" x 7 1/4"; Spragg, Isaac
    Phila., D.S. 2p. Witnessed by: Robt. Aitken, Frd. Sumfield, Matth. Clarkson. Cert. Bequest to Francis Hopkinson, and his appointment as executor.
  - Letter to Thomas Fisher, Dec. 16, 1773; 7 1/4" x 9"; Read, Charles, 1715-1774
    St. Croix, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Laments circumstances which have prevented his enjoying a life of ease.
  - Accounts of Treasurer Committee of Twelve with Benjamin Franklin, 1773-1800; 13x8-1/2; Society of Friends. Philadelphia meeting
    Xerox of D. 2p. Presented by Willman Spawn; 1968. FILM 54-65 FRAME 250
  - Letter to Wm. and Thos. Bradford, Feb. 28, 1774; 7" x 8 3/4"; Romans, Bernard, ca. 1720-ca. 1784
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Desires to know if the drawings sent to Owen Biddle for the Transactions of the American society were received. His work [Concise natural history of east and west Florida] will soon be published. Orders for various books.
  - Bond to Samuel Richards for £184.14.6, March 29, 1774; 13" x7 3/4"; Richards, John
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 2p. and end. [Philadelphia] Printed by Robert Bell for William Woodhouse.
  - Letter to [John] Ro[d]gers, New York, Sept. 3, 1774; 12x7-1/2; Wright, Patience Lovell
    London, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end.in unknown hand. Concerning the public events of England and the colonies.
  - Letter to Rich[ar]d Bache, Jan. 9, 1775; 8" x 12 3/4"; Bache, Mary
    Preston, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Politics; family news; mentions Dr. Franklin. FILM 54-61 FRAME 204
  - To the Friends of freedom in the city of New-York...New York, May 2, 1775; 8 1/2" x 11"; Goddard, William, 1740-1817
    Typescript of printed broadside 1p. Diatribe against John Foxcroft, as master of posts in North America. Presented by E. M. Riley, Sept.1951. Evans:14068
  - Letter to Dear Bro.[Edward Shippen], May 6, 1775; 7 1/2" x 6 1/4"; Shippen, William, 1712-1801
    A.L.S. 2p. Return of Dr. Franklin; news of Congress and the war. FILM54-64 FRAME209
  - Letter to ----, July 31, 1775; 9 1/4" x 7 1/4"; Rockingham, Charles Watson-Wentworth, Marquis of, 1730-1782
    Wentworth, A.L.S. 4p. Recent actions of Americans should awaken minds of British toward more conciliatory measures. Experience should teach His Majesty that scheme to conquer America is impracticable. MICROFILM FRAME NO.662
  - N(evil) Maskelyne to (John) Ewing, August 4, 1775; 7 1/4" x 9"; Maskelyne, Nevil, 1732-1811
    Greenwich, 2 pp. address and endorsement. A.L.S. Letter from the Astronomer Royal regarding projected observatory to be erected at Philadelphia. Printed in A.P.S. Proceedings, IV, 98.
  - Declaration of independence, June, 1776; 14x8-1/2; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Facsimile of first draft. 4p.with notations by B.Franklin and J.Adams. Artotype, E. Bierstadt, N.Y.
  - Letter to ----, Feb.15, 1776; 9x7; Mifflin, Thomas, 1744-1800
    A.L.S. 1p. Has, by order of Washington, paid for ordnance being transported to camp. Business.
  - Resolutions addressed to Gen. Lee., Feb. 15 and 17, 1776; 13" x 8"; United States. Continental Congress
    A.D.S: Cha. Thomson, secretary; John Hancock, president. 2p. and end. Mutilated Pertain to the Committee of Congress appointed to proceed to Canada - Dr. Franklin, S. Chase and C. Carroll of Carrolltown; and instructions to Printed: Journals of the Continental congress. FILM54-66 FRAME99
  - Letter to Mrs. Elizabeth Partridge, Jan.6, 1776; 8" x 6 1/2"; Ward, Joseph, 1737-1812
    Camp At Roxbury, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Evacuation of Boston. Looks forward to a glorious peace.
  - Agreement of subscribers on debts and proceeds of the tavern, Feb. 9, 1776; 25x26-1/2; Philadelphia. City Tavern
    D.S.: John Nixon and 52 others. 1p. Parchment. Seals.
  - Letter to John Barry, April 11, 1776; United States. Continental Congress. Marine Committee
    Phila., Photostat of L.S.: John Hancock, Robt. Morris, Richard Henry Lee, et al. 1p. and add. Relative to prize sloop Edward.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Catharine] Greene, June 1, 1776; 13" x 8 1/4"; Mecom, Jane, 1712-1794
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Return of her brother [B. Franklin]. Temple, son of Gov. Franklin, came with him. News of family and friends. FILM54-63 FRAME96
  - Letter to Lady Juliana Penn, June 10, 1776; 8" x 13"; Tilghman, James, 1716-1793
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add.,end. His and his son's services to the Proprieters. Prospect in America gloomy.
  - Order to John Nixon & others to pay 150£ on order to Messrs. Worral & Alisson, June 15, 1776; 8 1/4" x 5"; Clymer, George, 1739-1813
    D.S.: Geo. Clymer, James Biddle (?) Owen Biddle. 1p. and end. Presented by Seymour Adelman, 1947.
  - Declaration of independence, July 4, 1776; United States. Continental Congress
    Photograph of original document with signatures. 1p.
  - Letter to [Patrick Henry], July 16, 1776; 8 1/4" x 13"; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
    Phila., A.L.S. 4p. The Declaration of independence and its implications. Loss of Canada. Comments on exclusion of clergy from [Virginia ?] legislature. Printed: APS Lib.Bull for 1951,p.251-2-in Butterfield,L.H Dr. Rush to Governor Henry… Film No. 529
  - Letter to ----, July 22, 1776; 7-1/4x6; Winthrop, John, 1714-1779
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Xerox copy. Concerning the ranking of the APS with similar European societies. Concerning a supposed "Catalogue for the press."
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sarah Wayne Robinson], Aug. 12, 1776; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796
    Ticonderoga, Photostat of A.L.S. 1p. Would like a letter from her husband. Sends love to the family. Introduces the bearer, Mr. Antill.
  - Letter to Rt. Randall, Oct. 3, 1776; 7 1/4" x 9"; Girard, Stephen, 1750-1831
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. In French. Business transactions.
  - Letter to Abr[aha]m Robinson, Philadelphia, Oct. 3, 1776; 7-1/2x6-1/2; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796
    Tyconderoga, Photostat of A.L.S. 3p.and add. Congratulates him on the marriage of his sister. Describes the state of the army, eagerly awaiting battle.
  - Commission issued to Henry Spes, October 4, 1776; 12 1/2" x 8 3/4"; Pennsylvania. Council of Safety
    appointing him second lieutenant of the boat, Washington...Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms. S: Tho. Wharton, junr., president, Jacob S. Howell, secretary. 1p. and end. Seal.
  - Letter to Capt. Thomas Robinson, Fort George, Nov. 5, 1776; 7-1/2x6; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796
    Ticonderoga, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p.and add. Sends news of the retreat of the British.
  - Letter to Filippo Pirri, Rome, Nov. 8, 1776; 8x6-1/4; Buffon, Georges Louis Leclerc, comte de, 1707-1788
    Montbard, L.S. 6p.and add. In French. Defends his scientific theories agains those of Fortis, Spallanzani, Fontana, etc.
  - [Astronomical notes], 1766; Smith, William, 1727-1803
    Including astronomical observations, eclipse of the sun January 9, 1777; and eclipse of the sun June 24, 1778. 7p. Q. Manuscript. ( Mentions the American philosophical society.
    This manuscript document is in Mayer, J.T. Tabulae motuum solis et lunae...1770, c.1; Call Number: 524 M45t
  - Diary, Feb. 26-March 16, 1777?; 13x8-1/2; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Typed D. 11p. For original, see: B:H97d.1
  - Letter to Ab[raha]m Robinson, April 1, 1777; 12-1/4x8; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796
    Ticonderoga, Photostat of A.L.S. 2p.and add. Describes his "army" and hopes of victory.
  - Letter to Dr. [John] Calder, July 17, 1777; 6 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804
    Calne, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Seal. His contributions to an encyclopaedia. Religious bill just passed by Parliament. Arrival of scientific apparatus.
  - Letter to John Page, Aug. 18, 1777; 8 1/2" x 13"; Rittenhouse, David, 1732-1796
    Philadelphia, Typed L. 2p. and title. Astronomical matters. Presented by W. B. Montague, ca. June 1924. Not Found: 1/4/2011
  - Letter to Gen. [William] Whipple, Dec. 11, 1777; Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792
    Nantes, Photo.of A.L.S. 3p. (from glass negatives formerly in possession of Miss Frances M. Bradford.) Reports on trip of the Ranger. Refers to U.S. Commissioners. Presented by Miss Bradford; Oct.1961. FILM54-65 FRAME 223
  - Firman appointing an Imam to a mosque in Smyrna, [1777]; 24-1/2x17-3/4; Abdul Hamid, Sultan of the Turks, 1773-1789
    D.S. 1p.and end.and end. by J. Vaughan. In Turkish. English translation. Deposited by John P. Brown; Feb.19,1836 Cf.Minutes, p.681. Film 932
  - Reflections upon the military preparations which are making at present in Scotland, for the war in America, 1777; 12-3/4x8; Dalrymple, John, Sir, 1726-1810
    [ca.?]. D. 4p. Copy.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Jane Collas], April, 1778; Mecom, Jane, 1712-1794
    Coventry, Photostat of copy of L. (inc.) 3p. From copy in New England historic genealogical society. Contains also copy of letter of May 16, 1778. Printed:Van Doren,Franklin-Mecom, pp.174-176.
  - Letter to Henry Laurens, March 10, 1778; 6 1/2" x 8"; Ettwein, John, 1721-1802
    Bethlehem, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Relative to passport for two of the Brethren to go to Fort Pitt and the Delaware Nation.
  - Letter to Mrs. Jane Collas, May 16, 1778; Mecom, Jane, 1712-1794
    Warwick, Photostat of copy of L. 4p. Mentions her brother [Dr. Franklin] and Mrs. [Catharine] Greene. From copy in New England historic genealogical society. On same sheet with letter of April 1778.
  - Letter to D'Hupay de Fureau, St. Catherine, Près La Tour, June 8, 1778; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Ruault, Nicolas, 1742?-1828
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. In French. Will not write for him, but recommends Bonhomme Richard. Concerning Franklin. FILM54-67 FRAME49
  - Receipt to [Caleb] Gibbs for all demands against George Washington for house, furniture, etc., June 18, 1778; Hewes, Deborah
    Valley Forge, Photo. of D.S. 1p. (from glass negative formerly in possession of Miss Frances M. Bradford.) Presented by Miss Bradford; Oct.1961.
  - Resolution, Oct. 22, 1778; 7 1/4" x 9 1/2"; United States. Continental Congress
    D.S: Cha. Thomson, secretary 1p. Instructions to the Minister Plenipotentiary to the Court of France [B.Franklin] and the commissioners to other Courts to cultivate harmony and good understanding between various officials. Printed: Journals of Continental congress. FILM54-66 FRAME98
  - Letter to John Montagu, 4th earl of Sandwich, Nov. 24, 1778; Blair, John
    Horton, A.L.S. 1p. Indicates that he will give his "vote for Mr. Banks to be President of the Royal Society."
  - A case on gastritis as arising from dyspepsie., [1778]; 8 1/2" x 14"; Logan, George, 1753-1821
    Photostat of A.D.S 7p. From original - Dissertations II (1778), Royal medical society of Edinburgh.
  - [Dissertation on the small pox, 1778; Logan, George, 1753-1821
    Photostat of D. 5 leaves. From original in Royal medical society of Edinburgh, Dissertations, 11,1778.
  - Oaths sworn by Nathaniel Green, 1778; United States. Oath of allegiance
    Benedict Arnold; William Alexander; Arthur St. Clair; Benjamin Lincoln, Marquis de Lafayette; George Washington; Charles Lee; William Maxwell; William Smallwood; Enoch Poor; James Mitchell Varnum; John Paterson Anthony Wayne; Baron De Kalb; Lachlan McIntosh; and Baron Steuben; 1778. Photo.of printed D.filled in in ms.S. Witnessed in large part by G.Washington. 18 items. Presented by Mrs. Sioussat from the papers of Dr. St. George L. Sioussat; April 1961.
  - U.S. Oathes of allegiance, 1778; United States. Oath of allegiance
  - Summary of the memorial relative to the establishment & instruction of a corps of bombardiers, 1778 - 1779; 13 1/2" x 8 1/4"; Garanger, Lewis
    ca. A (?)D. 5p. Mentions Dr. Franklin and M. du Coudray. (May have been sent to Gen. Washington or Gen. Knox; cf. references in index to Garanger in Fitzpatrick) FILM 54-64 FRAME 201
  - Letter to Mr.Tofield, Jan. 8, 1779; Lightfoot, John, 1735-1788
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sarah] Bache, Jan. 17, 1779; Mecom, Jane, 1712-1794
    Warwick, photostat of c. of L. 1p. 2 c. Is anxious for news of them. Hears from others about her brother [B. Franklin]. From copy in Yale university library. Printed:Van Doren Franklin-Mecom,p.187. FILM54-65 FRAME 69
  - Will, Feb. 6, 1779; Poole, William
    Photo.of D.S. 5p. From original in Public Archives Commission, Dover, Del.
  - Resolutions, Feb. 25, 1779; 12 3/4" x 8"; United States. Continental Congress
    D.S: Cha. Thomson, secy. 2p. and end. For the raising of five companies of rangers to protect the frontiers of Pennsylvania from the savages.
  - Description of memoir on medical electricity, March 7, 1779; Bertholon, Pierre
    A.N.S. 1p. and note by La Tourrette. In French.
  - Letter to Major Gen. Greene, April 26, 1779; Greene, William, 1731-1809
    Providence, Photostat of c. of L. 1p. Relative to marching orders for Gen. Glover's troops. From original in possession of the Henry E. Huntington library.
  - Letter to Owen Biddle, Philadelphia, June 30, 1779; 13x8; Freehauff, Daniel
    Philadelphia, Xerox of ALS 1p. and add., end. Forwards observations on eclipse of the moon for him to show the APS if deemed worthy. Refers to Rittenhouse. Original in Owen Biddle Papers, Friends Hist. Library, Swarthmore College.
  - Letter to Richard Bache, July 21, 1779; Mecom, Jane Franklin, 1712-1794
  - Pass issued to Mr. Burchsdorff, of the German convention troops, Aug. 25, 1779; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826
    Photo. of A.D.S. 1p. (from original in possession of the Century Association, N.Y.)
  - Letter to Tho[ma]s Mumford, Aug. 28, 1779; 9" x 7"; Parsons, Samuel Holden, 1737-1789
    Highlands, A.L.S. 4p., end. and enc. Election of members of Congress; encloses a list of nominees. Objections to actions of present members, including the opposition to the recall of Arthur Lee.
  - Promissory note, Sept. 4, 1779; Beaumarchais, Pierre Augustin Caron de, 1732-1799
    A.N.S. 1p. In French.
  - Letter to Robert Morris, Oct. 13, 1779; 7" x 9 1/4"; Jones, John Paul, 1747-1792
    Amsterdam, Facsimile of A.L.S. 4p. News of his activities including the battle between the Bon Homme Richard and the Serapis on Sept. 23; mentions Dr. Franklin. FILM54-65 FRAME 71
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, November, 1779; 8" x 12 1/2"; Madison, James, 1749-1812
    William & Mary College, Virginia, A.Dr, of L.S. 4p. Transmits observations on the climate. Cause of aurora borealis; quotes Dr. Franklin on that and on body heat. Transmits barometrical observations by Mr. Jefferson. Note: Reverend James Madison of William and Mary College, not President James Madison, as identified by Dr. Thomas Shachtman, 9/20/2012. FILM 54-60 199 FRAME 429 13
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1779-1780; Bartram, John, 1699-1777
    Photostats of D. 4 items. (made from photostats in possession of F.D.West.) Pertaining to Bartram's estate. Presented by F.D.West; 1955.
  - Letter to Adam[o] Fabroni, Florence, Jan. 28, 1780; 9x7-1/4; Kirwan, Richard, 1733-1812
    London, A.L.S. 1p.and add. In French. Scientific news of London. Refers to cement, Royal Society, Crell, Priestley, etc. On same sheet is letter from Magellan to Fabroni; Feb. 4, 1780.
  - Letter to J. Bell, Edinburgh, Jan. 29, 1780; 8 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Murray, John, 1742-1793
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Book account Presented by Edgar R. McCorkle.
  - Letter to [Adamo Fabroni], Feb. 4, 1780; 9x7-1/4; Magalhães, João Jacinto de, 1723-1790
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Concerning chemistry and air. Refers to Fontana and Scopoli. His work on barometers. On same sheet as Kirwan to A.Fabroni; Jan. 28, 1780.
  - Letter to [Elbridge Gerry], March 13, 1780; 11x8-1/2; Adams, Abigail, 1744-1818
    Braintree, Typed L. 1p Copy. Would like to know why John Jay's name was placed before that of John Adams on list of A.P.S. From original in Penna.State Library, Harrisburg. Photo.in H.S.P.
  - Letter to [Giovanni Battista] Beccaria, March 28, 1780; 5 1/2" x 8"; Saussure, Horace Bénédict de, 1740-1799
    Geneve, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Seal. Introduces Mr. Trembley
  - Letter to Simeon Deane, April 7, 1780; 8 1/2" x 6 1/2"; Bancroft, Edward, 1744-1821
    Passy, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Shipment of medicines and drugs.
  - Minutes (extract) authorizing Josiah Hewes and Joseph Stanbury to obtain safe passage for books from New York, April 11, 1780; 7-1/2x8; Library Company of Philadelphia
    A.D.S.: Andrew Robeson, Secy. 1p.and end.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Abigail] Adams, April 17, 1780; 11 3/4" x 7 1/4"; Gerry, Elbridge, 1744-1814
    Phila., A.Dr. of L.S. with initials 4p. Comments on the press notice concerning Mr. Adams' election to the APS; difference in titles. Mentions Dr. Franklin. FILM54-64 FRAME 146
  - Receipt for gunpowder, June 14, 1780; 6-1/2x7-1/2; France. Bureau général des Poudres & Salpétres à Marseille
    Printed D.filled in in ms. 1p. In French. Was this for the American revolutionary forces?
  - Letter to "Dear Sir", July 4, 1780; Milne, Colin, 1743 or 4-1815
    Deptford, A.L.S. 2p. Speaks of the "illiberal attack upon my Sermons...[by] an anonymous Assassin of my own profession..."
  - Letter to --, Sept. 20, 1780
  - Pass issued to John Anderson, Sept. 22, 1780; 10" x 7"; Arnold, Benedict, 1741-1801
    Head Quarters, Robinsons, Facsimile of A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [Henry Laurens], Sept., 1780; 13-1/2x8-1/4; Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804
    L.in hand of J.Vaughan. 6p. Copy. (see J.Vaughan. Day book; 1783, pp.18ff.) Concerning Major André.
  - Letter to Ab[raha]m Robinson, Oct. 1, 1780; 13-3/4x8-1/2; Wayne, Anthony, 1745-1796
    Photostat of A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning Arnold and his perfidy. War around West Point.
  - Promissory note to William Webb, Nov. 10, 1780; 4x8-3/4; United States. Continental Loan Office
    Printed D.S.: F.Hopkinson,Treasr.of Loans and countersigned by Tho.Smith. 1p.and end.Wm.Webb and John Still---(?).
  - Letter to David Rittenhouse, Dec. 15, 1780; 8 3/4" x 10"; Muhlenberg, Frederick Augustus Conrad, 1750-1801
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Order to pay George Evans for the collation for the president.
    Not Found: 1/4/2011
  - Letter to Jean Fabroni, Florence, Dec. 20, 1780; 8x6-1/2; Magalhães, João Jacinto de, 1722-1790
    A.L.S. 3p.and add. In French. Current scientific events. Magnesium. Refers to John Fothergill, the Royal Society, James Watt, Joseph Priestley, Richard Kirwan and Benjamin Vaughan.
  - Loan office bill, issued to Isaac Coxe, Dec. 30, 1780; 8" x 4"; United States. Treasurer of Loans
    Printed D. filled in, S: F. Hopkinson. Drawn on "Dr. Benjamin Franklin, or the Minister Plenipotentiary of the United States of North-America, at the Court of Versailles." 1p. and end. FILM 54-61 FRAME 205
  - Letter to [Sarah Bache, 1780; Mecom, Jane, 1712-1794
    ca.]. Photostat of c. of L. 2p. incom. 2 c, Izard's accusations against Franklin. Family news. Mentions Mrs. Greene. From copy in Yale university library. printed:Van Doren,Franklin-Mecom,pp.201-204. FILM54-65 FRAME 73
  - [Loan slip in the form of a promissory note], 1780; 2 1/4" x 6 1/4"; Library Company of Philadelphia
    Printed D. filled in in ms. 1p. and end. Books borrowed by Benjamin Rush, May - Aug. 1780.
  - Acts of the Pennsylvania legislature concerning the American philosophical society, 1780-1843; Pennsylvania. Laws, statutes, etc.
    Photostats of D. 12p. (from original in Harrisburg.)
  - Letter to Daniel Clymer, Caernarvon, Jan.1, 1781; 8" x 6 1/2"; Biddle, James, 1731-1797
    Reading, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Invitation to visit.
  - Letter to Mr. Rathbone, Jr., Liverpool, Feb. 16, 1781; 11x8-1/2; Withering, William, 1741-1799
    Birmingham, Typed L. 2p. Copy. Xerox copy. Experiments on phlogiston and oxygen. Refers to fellow scientists and experiments. Refers to Joseph Priestley. On same sheet is letter from Withering to George Robinson; Oct. 14, 1798.
  - Letter to M. [Ferdinand] Grand, April 30, 1781; 8" x 11 1/2"; Jay, John, 1745-1829
    Madrid, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Seal. Contains French translation. Has drawn a bill of 487, 320 livres in favor of the Marquis de Yranda; has advised Dr. Franklin of this. FILM54-61 FRAME206
  - Letter to ----, May 19, 1781; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    A.L.S. 1p. Letter-press copy. Business of the Board of Longitude.
  - Letter to John page, June 4, 1781; 7 1/2" x 9"; Lee, Arthur, 1740-1792
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. with initials. 2p. Arrival of French fleet at Martinique. Dr. Franklin and French court plotting against Mr. J. Adams. FILM54-61 FRAME207
  - Letter to Owen Biddle, June 29, 1781; Wharton, Samuel, 1732-1800